Guide to the George Mason University Office of the President records, 1949-2004
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 7: Alan G. Merten, 1990-2004, (25 boxes)
  - Electronic campus of Virginia, October 13, 2000 (Box 116, Folder 11)
  - Electronic commerce advisory commission, 1998-1999 (Box 116, Folder 12)
  - Employee of the month, 1994-1999 (Box 116, Folder 13)
  - "Engaging the future", George Mason University, 1997-1998 (Box 116, Folder 14)
  - Engaging the future: Report of the President's faculty task force on the future of the University, 1997 (Box 116, Folder 15)
  - Engaging the future: Report of the President's faculty task force on the future of the University, 1997 (Box 116, Folder 16)
    see also 125.36
  - Equity office, 1995-1997 (Box 116, Folder 17)
  - Equity office, concerns, 1990, 1996 (Box 116, Folder 18)
  - Facilities, 1995-1996 (Box 116, Folder 19)
  - Fairfax county development authority, September 2001 (Box 116, Folder 20)
  - Fairfax county general, school system, 1995-1999 (Box 116, Folder 21)
  - Federal city council, 1994-1998 (Box 116, Folder 22)
  - Federal relations, briefing book, 1997 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Financial aid: Rhodes scholarships, 1997 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - Financial aid: UDALL, 1997 (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - First Virginia Bank, 1995-1998 (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Fiscal operations report, 1995-1996 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - The Ford Foundation, December 1996 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Fordice case, December 1996 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Forum on fusion science and technology, 1997 (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Frank, Barbara Joyce, 1998 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Freedom forum, November 1996 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Freeman, Neal B., 2001 (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Frye, Billy, 1999 (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Fulton, Richard L., 1998 (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Fuisz technology, 1996 (Box 117, Folder 14)
  - Fujitsu, 1998 (Box 117, Folder 15)
  - Gala George Mason University, June 7, 1996 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Galluzzo, Gary, 1999 (Box 118, Folder 2)
  - Gantz, Donald, 1996 (Box 118, Folder 3)
  - George Mason Bank, 1996 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - George Mason University 1949-1972, 2001 (Box 118, Folder 5)
  - George Mason Universtiy commencement honorary degree recepients, May 17, 2003 (Box 118, Folder 6)
  - George Mason University Foundation, 1998-2000 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Germany, 1998 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Graduating senior survey, Fall 1996 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Greater Washington business phianthropy summit, 1998 (Box 118, Folder 10)
  - Greater Washington higher education initiative, 2001 (Box 118, Folder 11)
  - GTE government systems, 1996-1998 (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - Hampton roads partnership, 1997 (Box 118, Folder 13)
  - Hampton roads partnership, 1997 (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Hampton roads, "Enhancing the relationship between NoVA roundtable and Hampton roads partnership", September 5-6, 1997 (Box 118, Folder 15)
  - Hazel, John T. Jr., 1998 (Box 118, Folder 16)
  - Health manpower planning, 1999 (Box 118, Folder 17)
  - Higher education bond referendum, 2002 (Box 118, Folder 18)
  - Highlands forum, December 1996 (Box 118, Folder 19)
  - Hillel, November 1996 (Box 118, Folder 20)
  - Hispanic association of colleges and universities, 1997 (Box 118, Folder 21)
  - Holland and Knight, 1998 (Box 118, Folder 22)
  - Honor code, 1997 (Box 118, Folder 23)
  - Horatio Alger association, 1995-1997 (Box 118, Folder 24)
  - Hu, Jason, 2000 (Box 118, Folder 25)
  - Hungary, 1998 (Box 118, Folder 26)
  - Imagining America, President's council, 2000 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Indian CEO, high tech council, 1999 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - The Indus group, inc., 1997-1998 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - University-industry relationships in the United States, June 1997 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Information systems security, 2000 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Information technology, University, 1992-1995 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - IT workforce [1 of 2], 1999-2000 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - IT workforce [2 of 2], 1999-2000 (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - IT workforce, "Building a workforce for the information economy" draft [1 of 2], October 21, 2000 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - IT workforce, needs study [2 of 2], 1999-2000 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Inova health system, 1996-2001 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Institute for defense analysis, 1999 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Institute of international education, December 1996 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Instructional development, 1996-1997 (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Internet policy [1 of 3], 1998-1999 (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Internet policy [2 of 3], 1998-1999 (Box 120, Folder 8)
  - Internet policy [3 of 3], 1999 (Box 120, Folder 9)
  - Invitation for Merten and Faculty Senate at the Mathy House, August 21, 1996 (Box 120, Folder 10)
  - Invitations, 1998-2006 (Box 120, Folder 11)
  - Isen, Alice M., 1997 (Box 120, Folder 12)
  - Jones, Thomas W., May 20, 1997 (Box 120, Folder 13)
  - The Johnson Foundation, 1997 (Box 120, Folder 14)
  - The Journal newspapers, 1997-1998 (Box 120, Folder 15)
  - JSTOR, December 1996 (Box 120, Folder 16)
  - Kaludis consulting group, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Keys and security, July 1996 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Khim, Jay W., 1999 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - The Knight collaborative, 1997-1998 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - KPMG, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 5)
  - Law school building dedication, March 24, 1999 (Box 121, Folder 6)
  - Learning Tree international, 1995-1997 (Box 121, Folder 7)
  - Library of Congress, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Lipset, Seymour, April 1996 (Box 121, Folder 9)
  - Lockheed Martin, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 10)
  - Logistics management institute, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 11)
  - Loudoun county, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 12)
  - Main Street America Group annual report, 2000 (Box 121, Folder 13)
  - Malawer, Stuart, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 14)
  - Management practice, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 15)
  - Marketing plan, November 2, 2000 (Box 121, Folder 16)
  - Mason Scholar selection committee, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 17)
  - Mason Scholar selection committee, 1999 (Box 121, Folder 18)
  - Mathy, Joseph, October 1996 (Box 121, Folder 19)
  - Maurelli, Joseph, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 20)
  - Mayer associates, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 21)
  - Mayor John Mason, 1999 (Box 121, Folder 22)
  - McGuire Woods consulting, 1999 (Box 121, Folder 23)
  - Media authorizing center, project ADEL (animated dance event language), December 10, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 24)
  - Media contacts: Business week, "Creating a new vision", October 6-8, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 25)
  - Media contracts: Chronicle of Higher Education, June 9, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 26)
  - Media general cable, 1998 (Box 121, Folder 27)
  - Media relations, 1996 (Box 121, Folder 28)
  - Media sciences research institute, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 29)
  - Mellon Foundation, 1996-2001 (Box 121, Folder 30)
  - Melton, William, 1998 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum from the Office of Associate Vice President, 1997 (Box 122, Folder 2)
  - Metropolitan University group consortium, 1997 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Milestone communications, 2001 (Box 122, Folder 4)
  - Minority advisory board, 1995-2001 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Minority student affairs, 1996-2000 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - Mishkin, Jeffrey, 2001 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Mobil corporation, 1996 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - NAFSA association of international educators, 1998 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - NASA, 1995-2000 (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - NACUBO, 1996-1998 (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - National council for accreditation of teacher education, 1999 (Box 122, Folder 12)
  - National science foundation, 1996-1998 (Box 122, Folder 13)
  - Nations bank, 1995-1996 (Box 122, Folder 14)
  - The Nature conservatory, 1998 (Box 122, Folder 15)
  - North campus history Fairfax circle, 1970s-2006 (Box 122, Folder 16)
  - Northern Virginia regional partnership [1 of 2], 1998-2000 (Box 122, Folder 17)
  - Northern Virginia regional partnership [2 of 2], 1998-2000 (Box 122, Folder 18)
  - Notices and correspondence, 2005 (Box 122, Folder 19)
  - O'Brian, Hugh, 2001 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - O'Connell, Frank J., March 1998 (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - Office of the Comptroller, 1992, 1997 (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - From the Office of the Vice President: "Restructuring instructional technology support", 1997 (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - Old Dominion University, 1997 (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - Open source solutions, inc., 1996-1997 (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - Oracle corporation, 1999 (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - Outside income statement, 1999-2000 (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Pankoff, Lyn D., December 1996 (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - Parking services: parking partnership, 1997 (Box 123, Folder 10)
  - Parking services: student concerns, 1996 (Box 123, Folder 11)
  - Parks, Lewis W., 1998 (Box 123, Folder 12)
  - Partnerships: BDM international, 1996 (Box 123, Folder 13)
  - Partnerships: Partnerships as policy: a report, January 13, 1997 (Box 123, Folder 14)
  - Partnerships: School partnership task force, September 25, 1996 (Box 123, Folder 15)
  - Patton Boggs: Federal relations review, 1999-2000 (Box 123, Folder 16)
  - Payne, L. F., 1997 (Box 123, Folder 17)
  - Pendray, John, 1996 (Box 123, Folder 18)
  - Performance measures, 1998-1999 (Box 123, Folder 19)
  - Peterson's annual survey of higher education personnel, 1997 (Box 123, Folder 20)
  - PEW roundtable, 1995-1996 (Box 123, Folder 21)
  - PEW leadership award, 1996 (Box 123, Folder 22)
  - Piedmont, Virginia Community College, 1998 (Box 123, Folder 23)
  - The Potomac conference, 1999 (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - The Potomac conference [1 of 3], 2000-2001 (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - The Potomac conference [2 of 3], 2000-2001 (Box 124, Folder 3)
  - The Potomac conference [3 of 3], 2000-2001 (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - Potomac knowledge way [1 of 2], 1996-1999 (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - Potomac knowledge way [2 of 2], 1996-1999 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Potomac regional education partnership, 1998 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Potomac river basin consortium, 1997 (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - Potomac yard, 1996 (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - Potts, Russ, circa 1996 (Box 124, Folder 10)
  - Prince William county, 1996-1999 (Box 124, Folder 11)
  - Prince William county legislative program, 1998 (Box 124, Folder 12)
  - Privitization and outsourcing, 1994-1997 (Box 124, Folder 13)
  - Professional development, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - The professional group, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Program assessment notes, undated (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Program on social and organizational learning (PSOL), 1995-1996 (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - Purple, William C., November 1996 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Ramphell, Mamphela, 1999 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Ratchford, Thomas, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Ratheon E-systems, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 8)
  - Recycling, 1992-1996 (Box 125, Folder 9)
  - Redmon Group, 1997 (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - Reed, Charles B., 1997 (Box 125, Folder 11)
  - Regardie's Power internet 100, article, May-June 2000 (Box 125, Folder 12)
  - Regional competitiveness program, 1997 (Box 125, Folder 13)
  - Reorganization, 1998 (Box 125, Folder 14)
  - Representative Frank Wolf traffic concerns I-66, May 3, 1999 (Box 125, Folder 15)
  - "Richmond at the crossroads", August 31, 1998 (Box 125, Folder 16)
  - Richmond Times dispatch, 1997-1998 (Box 125, Folder 17)
  - Riggs national corporation, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 18)
  - Rotary international "Whitton Endowment", 1998 (Box 125, Folder 19)
  - Salaries: A comparative analysis, circa 2003 (Box 125, Folder 20)
  - Sallie Mae, 1998-1999 (Box 125, Folder 21)
  - Saskatchewan, 1999 (Box 125, Folder 22)
  - Saylor, Michael, 2000 (Box 125, Folder 23)
  - Scaldini, Richard, 1997 (Box 125, Folder 24)
  - Science applications international corporation, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 25)
  - Science policy, 1991-1996 (Box 125, Folder 26)
  - Sexual assault services (SAS) coordinator Connie J. Kirkland, 1995-1996 (Box 125, Folder 27)
  - Sexual harassment prevention, 2000 (Box 125, Folder 28)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS), 1999 (Box 125, Folder 29)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (SACS) self-study, 1999 (Box 125, Folder 30)
  - Spector and associates, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 31)
  - Sponsored research, 1997 (Box 125, Folder 32)
  - Sport in society, 1994-1996 (Box 125, Folder 33)
  - Statistics, November 8, 1996 (Box 125, Folder 34)
  - Strategic briefing meeting, June 10, 1999 (Box 125, Folder 35)
  - Task force on the future of the University, "Engaging the future" report, November 10, 1997 (Box 125, Folder 36)
  - Toffler associates, 2001 (Box 125, Folder 37)
  - Taylor, Anita, 1996 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Telephone message pads, June 2-March 28, year unknown (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Telephone message pads, June 25-November 9, year unknown (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Telephone message pads, October 12-March 10, year unknown (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Telephone message pads, October 29, 1997-April 29, 1998 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Telephone message pads, April 21, 1998-June 24, 1998 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Telephone message pads, Darry Cors, April 3, 1998-September 28, 1998 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Telephone message pads, April 29, 1998-October 27, 1998 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Telephone message pads, Trish Roney, February 16, 1998-April 21, 1998 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Telephone message pads, Cynthia Knight, October 27, 1998-June 30, 1999 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Telephone message pads, Darry Cors, September 28, 1998-June 1, 1999 (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Telephone message pads, Sharon Coardia, June 30, 1999-November 11, 1999 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Telephone message pads, March 15, 1999-September 11, 1999 (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Telephone message pads, Trish and Aimee Beverlein, August 13, 1999-January 10, 2000 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Telephone message pads, Aimee Beverlein, January 18, 2000-April 3, 2000 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Telephone message pads, Aimee Beverlein, April 3, 2000-July 25, 2000 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Telephone message pads, Aimee Beverlein, July 25, 2000-November 15, 2000 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - Telephone message pads, Darry Cors, March 28, 2000-January 22, 2001 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Telephone message pads, Aimee Beverlein, November 15, 2000-April 9, 2001 (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Telephone message pads, M.M., April 9, 2001-October 23, 2001 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - Tesco technology, 1996 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Thank you letters, 1999 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Three presidents symposium, 1997-1998 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Transfer guide, 1998 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Transportation Research Institute, 1996-1997 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Trefil, James article, September 1997 (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Trinidad and Tobago, 1998 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Tuition payment policy, 2002-2003 (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - Tuition rollback, 1998 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - UMUT Foundation in Turkey, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - United Nations, 2000 (Box 129, Folder 11)
  - U.S. News and World Report, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - University club, 1999 (Box 129, Folder 13)
  - University corporation for advanced internet development (UCAID), 1997 (Box 129, Folder 14)
  - University Life: Honors committee, August 4, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 15)
  - University Life: Indian Student Association, 1997 (Box 129, Folder 16)
  - University relations, 1992-1996 (Box 129, Folder 17)
  - Venture capitalists: Ed Mathias, 2000 (Box 129, Folder 18)
  - Venture capitalists: Gene Riechers, 2000 (Box 129, Folder 19)
  - Venture capitalists: Henry Barratt, 2000 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Venture capitalists: John Backus, 2000 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - Venture capitalists: Tim Meyers, 2001 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - Venture capitalists: Updata, 2000-2001 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Veridian awards banquet, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - Vietnam, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Virginia baseball club, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Virginia business, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Virginia business higher education council public FYI, July 1996 (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Virginia business magazine, undated (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Citizenship Institute, 2000 (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - Virginia economic bridge initiative, 1996-2000 (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - Virginia education, circa 1996 (Box 130, Folder 13)
  - Virginia international university, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 14)
  - Virginia pilot, 1996-1997 (Box 130, Folder 15)
  - Virginia police chiefs foundation, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 16)
  - Virginia technology council, 1996 (Box 130, Folder 17)
  - Virginia View (Virginia Tech), 1997 (Box 130, Folder 18)
  - "Virginia's list of leaders", Virginia business, 1994-1998 (Box 130, Folder 19)
  - Voice of America, 1998 (Box 130, Folder 20)
  - VSE corporation, 1996 (Box 130, Folder 21)
  - Warfield, John, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 22)
  - Washington advisory group, 1997-2001 (Box 130, Folder 23)
  - Washington business hall of fame, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 24)
  - Washington Business Journal, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 25)
  - Washington metro area transit, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 26)
  - The Washington Post, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 27)
  - The Washington Post, 1996-1997 (Box 130, Folder 28)
  - Washington regional education summit, 1999 (Box 130, Folder 29)
  - Washington Research Library Consortium (WRLC), 1997-2000 (Box 130, Folder 30)
  - Washington Research Library Consortium (WRLC), budget, 1994-1999 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - The Washington Times, 1997 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - The Washingtonian, 1996-1997 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - West Point, 1997 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - Whalen, James, 1997 (Box 131, Folder 5)
  - Wolf Trap Foundation, 1997 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Women's advisory board, 1996-2000 (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - Women's global challenge, 1999 (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - The Word Bank, 1997 (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - Workforce availability and education task force, 1997-1998 (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - World wide web design issues, 1996 (Box 131, Folder 11)
  - Wyoming, 1997 (Box 131, Folder 12)
  - Xerox, 1996-1997 (Box 131, Folder 13)
  - Yankee Energy System, inc., 1996-1997 (Box 131, Folder 14)
  - Young, April, 1996 (Box 131, Folder 15)